<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Alex Mantzaris (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- French updates made by Calvitix, to correct the original BTS File-->
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<!-- Text for additional events by Daniels "Solver" Umanovskis -->
	<!-- Thanks to the translators: Niessuh (Spanish), marioflag (Italian), Kai Fiebach (German), Masquerouge (French)! -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CIV_GAME</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective game designers have developed a new game of Civilization.</English>
		<French>Les développeurs de jeux vidéos %s1:3_civ_adjective ont créé une nouvelle version de Civilization.</French>
		<German>Von %s1:2_civ_adjective Entwicklern wird ein neuartiges Computerspiel namens 'Civilization' pr&#228;sentiert.</German>
		<Italian>Progettisti di videogiochi %s1_civ_adjective hanno sviluppato un nuovo gioco chiamato Civilization.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los dise&#241;adores de juegos %s1_civ_adjective han desarrollado un nuevo juego de Civilization.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CIV_GAME</Tag>
		<English>Our game designers have developed a new addictive game of Civilization. How shall we proceed?</English>
		<French>Nos développeurs de jeux vidéos on créé une nouvelle et addictive version de Civilization. Que devons-nous faire?</French>
		<German>Unsere Entwickler pr&#228;sentieren ein neuartiges Computerspiel namens 'Civilization'. Was meint Ihr dazu?</German>
		<Italian>I nostri progettisti di videogiochi hanno sviluppato un nuovo gioco chiamato Civilization. Cosa dobbiamo fare?</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros dise&#241;adores de juegos han desarrollado un nuevo juego de Civilization. &#191;Qu&#233; debemos hacer?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_1</Tag>
		<English>Send congratulations to the developers. Our people should enjoy this game.</English>
		<French>Envoyez nos félicitations aux développeurs. Notre bon peuple devrait apprecier ce jeu.</French>
		<German>&#220;bermittelt meine Gl&#252;ckw&#252;nsche. Unser Volk soll sich an dem Spiel erfreuen.</German>
		<German>&#220;bermittelt meine Gl&#252;ckw&#252;nsche. Unser Volk soll sich an dem Spiel erfreuen.</German>
		<Italian>Manda le nostre congratulazioni agli sviluppatori. La nostra gente si divertir&#224; con questo gioco.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Enviar felicitaciones a los desarrolladores. Nuestro pueblo disfrutar&#225; este juego.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_2</Tag>
		<English>This game seems to have great educational potential. Suggest that it be used in our educational system.</English>
		<French>Il semblerait que ce jeu aie un fort potentiel éducatif. Nous devrions l'utiliser dans notre système scolaire.</French>
		<German>Dieses Spiel scheint gro&#223;es Bildungspotential zu haben. Lasst es uns im Bildungswesen einsetzen.</German>
		<Italian>Questo gioco sembra avere un grande potenziale educativo. Propongo che venga usato nel nostro sistema scolastico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Este juego parece tener un gran potencial educacional. Sugerir que sea usado en nuestro sistema educativo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_3</Tag>
		<English>Computer games? They have no place in our society! Sell the franchise to foreign buyers!</English>
		<French>Des jeux vidéos? Pas de ça dans notre société! Vendez la franchise à des acheteurs étrangers!</French>
		<German>Computerspiele? So etwas verdirbt die Gesellschaft nur. Verkauft die Rechte ins Ausland!</German>
		<Italian>Giochi per computer? Non c'&#232; posto per loro nella nostra societ&#224;! Vendi la licenza ad acquirenti stranieri!</Italian>
		<Spanish>&#191;Juegos de ordenador? No tienen cabida en nuestra sociedad! Vender la franquicia a compradores extranjeros!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SLAVE_REVOLT_WARNING</Tag>
		<English>Sir, our slaves are on the verge of revolting! As long as our society continues to use slaves, there is a possibility of them revolting!</English>
		<French>Sire, nos esclaves sont sur le point de se révolter! Tant que notre société aura recours a l'esclavage, nous courrons le risque d'une révolte!</French>
		<German>Verzeiht, aber unsere Sklaven werden zunehmend unzufriedener! Solange unsere Gesellschaft die Sklaverei weiter praktiziert, laufen wir die Gefahr von Aufst&#228;nden!</German>
		<Italian>Signore, gli schiavi sono sull'orlo di una rivolta! Fino a quando la nostra societ&#224; continuer&#224; ad usare schiavi, ci sar&#224; la possibilit&#224; di una loro ribellione!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se&#241;or, nuestros esclavos est&#225;n a punto de rebelarse! Mientras nuestra sociedad siga usando esclavos, hay una posibilidad de que se rebelen!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_WARNING</Tag>
		<English>The slaves of %s2_city are on the verge of revolt!</English>
		<French>Les esclaves de la ville de %s2_city sont sur le point de se révolter.</French>
		<German>Die unterdr&#252;ckten Sklaven in %s2_city stehen am Rande eines Aufstandes!</German>
		<Italian>Gli schiavi di %s2_city sono sull'orlo di una rivolta!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los esclavos de %s2_city est&#225;n a punto de rebelarse!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_IMMIGRANTS</Tag>
		<English>Inspired by books telling stories about the culture of %s2_city, immigrants are flowing to the city!</English>
		<French>Motivés par ce qu'ils ont lu sur la culture de %s2_city, les immigrants y arrivent en masse!</French>
		<German>Geschichten &#252;ber die reiche Kultur der Stadt %s2_city ziehen viele Immigranten an.</German>
		<Italian>Ispirati dai libri che raccontano storie sulle bellezze culturali di %s2_city, un flusso di immigranti si dirige verso la citt&#224;!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Inspirados por libros que narran historias sobre la cultura de %s2_city, los inmigrantes est&#225;n inundando la ciudad!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_IMMIGRANTS</Tag>
		<English>Immigrants are flowing to %s2_city inspired by stories of its culture!</English>
		<French>Les immigrants arrivent en masse dans la ville de %s2_city, attirés par les histoires qu'ils ont lu sur sa culture!</French>
		<German>Geschichten &#252;ber die reiche Kultur der Stadt %s2_city ziehen viele Immigranten an.</German>
		<Italian>Un flusso di immigranti si dirige verso %s2_city ispirati da racconti sulle sue bellezze culturali!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los inmigrantes est&#225;n inundando %s2_city inspirados por libros que narran historias sobre su cultura!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMMIGRANTS_1</Tag>
		<English>We are pleased at their new choice of residence.</English>
		<French>Nous sommes ravis de leur décision de s'installer ici.</French>
		<German>Unsere lebendige Kultur erf&#252;llt mich mit Freude.</German>
		<Italian>Siamo soddisfatti per la loro scelta di trasferirsi nella citt&#224;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nos agrada que hayan elegido residir all&#237;.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HEALING_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective herbalists have discovered a plant that might result in better illness treatment.</English>
		<French>Les botanistes %s1:3_civ_adjective ont découvert une plante qui pourrait améliorer le traitement de certaines maladies.</French>
		<German>Von %s1:2_civ_adjective Naturheilkundigen wird die besondere Wirksamkeit einer Pflanze f&#252;r die Behandlung von Krankheiten entdeckt.</German>
		<Italian>Erboristi %s1_civ_adjective hanno scoperto una pianta che potrebbe risultare utile nella cura di alcune malattie.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Boticarios %s1_civ_adjective han descubierto una planta que puede servir para un mejor tratamiento de enfermedades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>Our herbalists have discovered a new plant that holds great promise for health treatments. However, tests on human subjects are required to find the right mixture.</English>
		<French>Nos botanistes ont découvert une nouvelle plante prometteuse pour la médecine. Cependant, des tests sur des humains sont requis pour trouver les dosages appropriés.</French>
		<German>Unsere Naturheilkundigen haben die besondere Wirksamkeit einer Pflanze f&#252;r die Behandlung von Krankheiten entdeckt. Es sind allerdings umfassende Feldversuche an Menschen erforderlich, die f&#252;r die Betroffenen nicht ungef&#228;hrlich sind.</German>
		<Italian>I nostri erboristi hanno scoperto una pianta che sembra avere un grande potenziale per un uso nel campo medico. Tuttavia, sono richiesti test su esseri umani per trovare la miscela giusta.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros boticarios han descubierto una nueva planta prometedora para tratar enfermedades. Sin embargo, es necesario pruebas en sujetos humanos para refinar la composici&#243;n.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_1</Tag>
		<English>Forget these tests. Anything worth knowing has already been discovered, so why risk needless death?</English>
		<French>Au diable les tests! Tout ce qui en vaut la peine à déja été découvert, alors pourquoi risquer des morts inutiles?</French>
		<German>Riskante Feldversuche kommen nicht in Frage. Wir setzen die Gesundheit von Menschen nicht aufs Spiel.</German>
		<Italian>Dimentica i test. Tutto ci&#242; che &#232; necessario nel campo medico &#232; gi&#224; stato scoperto, perch&#232; rischiare decessi inutili?</Italian>
		<Spanish>Olvida esas pruebas. Ya ha sido descubierto algo de valor, &#191;para qu&#233; arriesgarse con pruebas innecesarias?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_2</Tag>
		<English>Alright, try limited tests, but only on non-essential citizens.</English>
		<French>D'accord, lancez des tests restreints seulement sur des citoyens de seconde classe.</French>
		<German>Ich stimme begrenzten Tests zu, die sich auf unwesentliche B&#252;rger beschr&#228;nken.</German>
		<Italian>Va bene, diamo il via a test limitati, ma solo su cittadini "non essenziali".</Italian>
		<Spanish>De acuerdo, hagan pruebas limitadas, pero solo en ciudadanos no esenciales.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_3</Tag>
		<English>Health is the bedrock to world domination! Run full scale tests on all but the youngest and weakest among us.</English>
		<French>La santé est le pilier fondateur de toute domination mondiale! Lancez des tests à grande echelle sur tous nos citoyens adultes et en bonne santé!</French>
		<German>Ohne Risiko ist kein Fortschritt zu haben, und eine Gro&#223;macht braucht ein gesundes Volk! Lasst umfassende Versuchsreihen durchf&#252;hren, von denen nur die J&#252;ngsten und Schw&#228;chsten ausgenommen sind.</German>
		<Italian>La buona salute dei nostri cittadini &#232; uno dei fondamenti per la dominazione mondiale! Diamo il via a test su larga scala su tutte le persone eccetto i pi&#249; giovani e i pi&#249; deboli.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La salud es la base de la dominaci&#243;n mundial! Realicen pruebas completas en todos salvo los m&#225;s d&#233;biles</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_4</Tag>
		<English>In their attempts to find the right mixture of herbs, our healers caused fatalities throughout the empire!</English>
		<French>Les tentatives de nos chercheurs pour trouver le bon dosage de plantes ont causé de nombreuses morts dans notre empire!</French>
		<German>Umfassende Versuchsreihen f&#252;r ein neues Heilmittel verursachen Todesf&#228;lle im gesamten Reich! </German>
		<Italian>Durante i vari tentativi di trovare la giusta miscela di erbe, i nostri erboristi hanno causato la morte di diverse persone all'interno del nostro impero!</Italian>
		<Spanish>En su intento por refinar la composici&#243;n, nuestros sanitarios causan fallecimientos por todo el imperio!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_5</Tag>
		<English>Our experiments have been a success! Our cities now enjoy better healing herbs!</English>
		<French>Nos expériences ont réussi! Nos villes bénéficient désormais d'herbes médicinales améliorées!</French>
		<German>Die Versuchsreihen f&#252;r ein neues Heilmittel sind ein voller Erfolg. Die Gesundheit unserer St&#228;dte profitiert von den neuen Behandlungsm&#246;glichkeiten!</German>
		<Italian>I nostri esperimenti hanno avuto successo! Le nostre citt&#224; hanno ora a disposizione erbe curative di migliore qualit&#224;!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros experimentos han sido un &#233;xito! Nuestros ciudadanos ahora disfrutan de mejores hierbas curativas!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_6</Tag>
		<English>Our experiments have been a resounding success! We now posess much better treatments!</English>
		<French>Nos expériences ont réussi au-delà de nos espérances! Nous disposons désormais de meilleurs traitements!</French>
		<German>Die Versuchsreihen f&#252;r ein neues Heilmittel sind ein durchschlagender Erfolg. Wir besitzen jetzt deutlich bessere Behandlungsm&#246;glichkeiten!</German>
		<Italian>I nostri esperimenti hanno avuto un successo straordinario! Abbiamo ora a nostra disposizione cure molto migliori per alcune malattie!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros experimentos han sido un &#233;xito rotundo! Ahora poseemos tratamientos mucho mejores!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GREAT_BEAST</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective hunters have discovered a great beast lurking near one of their camps.</English>
		<French>Les chasseurs %s1:3_civ_adjective ont découvert une énorme bête rodant près d'un de leurs camps.</French>
		<German>Von %s1:2_civ_adjective J&#228;gern gibt es Berichte &#252;ber ein riesiges Tier, das sich in der N&#228;he eines Lagers gezeigt haben soll.</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatori %s1_civ_adjective hanno avvistato un grande animale appostato nei dintorni di un loro accampamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cazadores %s1_civ_adjective han descubierto una gran bestia acechando uno de sus campamentos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST</Tag>
		<English>A great beast has been discovered near one of our hunting camps.</English>
		<French>Un énorme animal a été découvert près d'un de nos camps de chasse.</French>
		<German>Ein riesiges Tier wurde in der N&#228;he eines unserer Lager gesichtet.</German>
		<Italian>Un grande animale &#232; stato avvistato nei dintorni di un nostro campo di caccia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Una gran bestia ha sido descubierta cerca de uno de nuestros campamentos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_1</Tag>
		<English>Let it breed and give offspring. Hunt sparingly.</English>
		<French>Laissez-la se reproduire, et chassez sa progéniture avec parcimonie.</French>
		<German>Lasst das Tier sich vermehren und die Nachkommen ma&#223;voll bejagen.</German>
		<Italian>Lasciate che si riproduca. Cacciate con moderazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Dejenle criar y tener descendencia. Cazar esporadicamente.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_2</Tag>
		<English>Looks like it could feed many people. Organize a hunting party!</English>
		<French>Sa viande pourrait nourrir beaucoup d'entre nous! Rassemblez nos chasseurs!</French>
		<German>Das Tier kann sicher viele Menschen satt werden. Organisiert eine Jagd!</German>
		<Italian>Potremmo dar da mangiare a diverse persone. Organizziamo una bella caccia!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Parece que podr&#237;a alimentar a mucha gente. Organizar una partida de caza!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_3</Tag>
		<English>Hunt it? Are you mad? The beast is a manifestation of a divine spirit!</English>
		<French>La chasser? Vous êtes fous? Cette bête est une manifestation divine!</French>
		<German>Das Tier zur Strecke bringen? Seid ihr von Sinnen? Dies ist eine Manifestation g&#246;ttlichen Wirkens!</German>
		<Italian>Cacciarlo? Sei matto? L'animale &#232; una manifestazione di uno spirito divino!</Italian>
		<Spanish>&#191;Cazarlo?&#191;Est&#225;as loco? La bestia es una maniestaci&#243;n de un esp&#237;ritu divino!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] in all cities with %F3_religion for %d2 [NUM2:turn:turns].</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] dans toutes les villes %F3_religion pendant %d2 [NUM2:tour:tours]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] in allen St&#228;dten mit der Religion %F3_religion f&#252;r %d2 [NUM2:Runde:Runden]</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] in tutte le citt&#224; con %F3_religion per %d2 [NUM2:turno:turni]</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] en todas las ciudades con %F3_religion por %d2 [NUM2:turno:turnos]</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective philosopher has stirred up controversy among the religious population.</English>
		<French>Un philosophe %s1_civ_adjective est à l'origine d'une controverse au sein de la population religieuse.</French>
		<German>Ein %[s1:3_civ_adjective]r Philosoph l&#246;st Kontroversen unter der religi&#246;sen Bev&#246;lkerung aus.</German>
		<Italian>Un filosofo %s1_civ_adjective ha scatenato una controversia tra i vari credenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un fil&#243;sofo %s1_civ_adjective ha levantado controversia entre la poblaci&#243;n religiosa.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER</Tag>
		<English>A philosopher from %s2_city is stirring up controversy among our population. Our people are highly distrustful of his teachings.</English>
		<French>Un philosophe de %s2_city a jeté le trouble parmi nos gens qui se méfient fortement de ses enseignements.</French>
		<German>Ein Philosoph aus %s2_city l&#246;st Kontroversen innerhalb unserer Bev&#246;lkerung aus. Seine Lehren machen die Leute argw&#246;hnisch.</German>
		<Italian>Un filosofo di %s2_city sta scatenando una controversia all'interno della nostra popolazione. I nostri cittadini sono molto diffidenti nei confronti dei suoi insegnamenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un fil&#243;sofo de %s2_city esta levantando controversia entre nuestra poblaci&#243;n. Nuestra gente esta realmente disgustada con sus ense&#241;anzas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_1</Tag>
		<English>We won't tolerate such heresy. Send him into exile!</English>
		<French>Nous ne tolèrerons aucune hérésie. Bannissez-le!</French>
		<German>Derartige Ketzerei wird nicht toleriert. Schickt ihn ins Exil!</German>
		<Italian>Non tollereremo un'eresia simile. Mandatelo in esilio!</Italian>
		<Spanish>No toleraremos tal herejia. Mandarlo al exilio!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_2</Tag>
		<English>He's a senile old fool. Let him teach if he wants to.</English>
		<French>Ce n'est qu'un vieux radoteur. Laissez-le enseigner s'il le souhaite.</French>
		<German>Der senile alte Narr soll lehren, was er will.</German>
		<Italian>&#200; un vecchio pazzo. Lasciatelo insegnare se vuole.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Es un viejo tonto senil. Dejadle ense&#241;ar si as&#237; lo desea.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_3</Tag>
		<English>That's one exceptional mind! Sponsor an Academy for him to teach!</English>
		<French>C'est un esprit exceptionnel! Proposons-lui une chaire où il puisse enseigner!</French>
		<German>W&#252;rdigt diesen au&#223;ergew&#246;hnlichen Geist durch die Errichtung einer eigenen Akademie!</German>
		<Italian>Quest'uomo &#232; dotato di una mente eccezionale. Mandatelo ad insegnare in un'accademia!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Es una mente excepcional! Patrocinar una Academia para sus ense&#241;anzas!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DEFECTING_AGENT</Tag>
		<English>A high-ranking %s1_civ_adjective intelligence agent has defected to the %s4_civ_adjective government.</English>
		<French>Un agent %s1_civ_adjective haut placé a déserté et a rejoint le gouvernement %s4_civ_adjective.</French>
		<German>Ein hochrangiger %[s1:3_civ_adjective]r Spion ist zum %s4:2_civ_adjective Reich &#252;bergelaufen.</German>
		<Italian>Un agente di grado elevato dell'intelligence %s1_civ_adjective ha disertato ed &#232; passato al servizio del governo %s4_civ_adjective.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un agente de inteligencia %s1_civ_adjective de alto rango ha desertado al gobierno %s4_civ_adjective.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT</Tag>
		<English>One of our high-ranking intelligence agents has defected to the %s1_civ_adjective empire.</English>
		<French>Un de nos agents haut placé a déserté nos rangs pour rejoindre l'empire %s1_civ_adjective.</French>
		<German>Einer unserer hochrangigen Spione ist zum %s1:2_civ_adjective Reich &#252;bergelaufen.</German>
		<Italian>Uno dei nostri agenti dell'intelligence di grado elevato ha disertato ed &#232; passato al servizio dell'impero %s1_civ_adjective</Italian>
		<Spanish>Uno de nuestros agentes de inteligencia de alto rango ha desertado al imperio %s1_civ_adjective</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT_1</Tag>
		<English>That's regrettable. We'll need to review our security procedures.</English>
		<French>C'est regrettable. Il nous faut revoir nos procédures de sécurité.</French>
		<German>Das ist bedauerlich. Lasst die Sicherheitsma&#223;nahmen &#252;berpr&#252;fen.</German>
		<Italian>&#200; una cosa deplorevole. Dovremo rivedere le nostre misure di sicurezza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Es lamentable. Tendremos que revisar nuestros procedimientos de seguridad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT_2</Tag>
		<English>Unacceptable. An "accident" should happen to the traitor!</English>
		<French>Intolérable. Un "accident" devrait arriver au traître!</French>
		<German>Das ist inakzeptabel. Sorgt f&#252;r einen "Unfall" des Verr&#228;ters...</German>
		<Italian>&#200; inaccettabile. Il traditore la deve pagare!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Inaceptable. El traidor debe sufrir un "accidente"!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_JAIL</Tag>
		<English>The citizens of %s2_city are worried about their safety because of the city's Jail.</English>
		<French>Les habitants de %s2_city sont inquiets pour leur sécurité à cause de la prison municipale.</French>
		<German>Die B&#252;rger von %s2_city sind wegen des Gef&#228;ngnisses der Stadt hinsichtlich ihrer Sicherheit besorgt.</German>
		<Italian>I cittadini di %s2_city sono preoccupati per la loro sicurezza a causa della Prigione cittadina.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los ciudadanos de %s2_city est&#225;n preocupados por su seguridad debido a la carcel de la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL</Tag>
		<English>People of %s2_city are not feeling safe. They are worried that criminals may escape from the local Jail.</English>
		<French>Les habitants de %s2_city ne se sentent pas en sécurité. La possibilité que des criminels s'échappent de la prison locale les inquiète.</French>
		<German>Die B&#252;rger von %s2_city sorgen sich hinsichtlich der Sicherheit des st&#228;dtischen Gef&#228;ngnisses.</German>
		<Italian>I cittadini di %s2_city non si sentono sicuri. Sono preoccupati che i criminali possano scappare dalla Prigione locale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La gente de %s2_city no se siente segura. Les preocupes que los criminales escapen de la carcel local.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL_1</Tag>
		<English>So what? No one is going to escape anyway.</English>
		<French>Et alors? Personne ne va s'échapper de toutes façons.</French>
		<German>Die Leute sehen Gespenster. Ich habe andere Sorgen.</German>
		<Italian>Quindi? In ogni caso nessuno uscir&#224; da quella prigione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>&#191;Y qu&#233;? Nadie va a escapar de ah&#237;.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL_2</Tag>
		<English>Boost jail security and organize a campaign to convince the citizens that they're safe.</English>
		<French>Améliorez la sécurité pénitentiaire et organisez une campagne de communication pour convainvre les gens qu'ils sont en sûreté.</French>
		<German>Verst&#228;rkt die Gef&#228;ngnissicherheit und organisiert eine Kampagne, um die B&#252;rger von der Sicherheit zu &#252;berzeugen.</German>
		<Italian>Potenzia la sicurezza nella prigione e organizza una campagna propagandistica per rassicurare i cittadini.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Incrementa la seguridad de la carcel y organiza una campa&#241;a para convencer a los ciudadanos de que est&#225;n seguros.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SPY_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>A %s4_civ_adjective infiltrator has been dicovered in the %s1_civ_adjective government.</English>
		<French>Un infiltrateur %s4_civ_adjective a été découvert au sein du gouvernement %s1_civ_adjective</French>
		<German>In den Reihen der %s1:2_civ_adjective Regierung ist ein %[s4:3_civ_adjective]r Spion enttarnt worden.</German>
		<Italian>Un infiltratore %s4_civ_adjective &#232; stato scoperto all'interno del governo %s1_civ_adjective</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un infiltrado %s4_civ_adjective ha sido descubierto en el gobierno %s1_civ_adjective.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective spy is operating on a high level in our government! What should we do?</English>
		<French>Un espion %s1_civ_adjective est implanté dans les plus hautes sphères de notre gouvernement! Que devons-nous faire?</French>
		<German>Einer Eurer Regierungsmitarbeiter ist als %[s1:3_civ_adjective]r Spion enttarnt worden! Was wollt Ihr tun?</German>
		<Italian>Una spia %s1_civ_adjective sta operando negli alti livelli del nostro governo.Cosa dobiamo fare?</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un espia %s1_civ_adjective esta operando a alto nivel en nuestro gobierno! &#191;Qu&#233; debemos hacer?</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_1</Tag>
		<English>Be discreet. Offer the to release the spy to their government, but question him first.</English>
		<French>Soyez discrets. Offrez de rendre l'espion a son gouvernement, mais questionnez-le d'abord.</French>
		<German>Seid diskret. Bietet die Ausweisung des Spions an, aber verh&#246;rt ihn gr&#252;ndlich.</German>
		<Italian>Agiamo con discrezione. Offriamo al loro governo il rilascio della spia, dopo averlo interrogato.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Seamos discretos. Entregar el espia a su gobierno, pero interrogadlo primero.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_2</Tag>
		<English>Every man has his price. His knowledge could make him a very valuable asset.</English>
		<French>Personne n'est incorruptible. Ses connaissances pourraient nous être précieuses.</French>
		<German>Jeder ist k&#228;uflich. Dieser Spion wird uns noch n&#252;tzlich sein.</German>
		<Italian>Ogni uomo ha un suo prezzo. Le sue conoscenze potrebbero tornarci molto utili.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Todo el mundo tiene su precio. Su conocimiento puede hacerle un recurso muy valioso.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_3</Tag>
		<English>That is an act of war! Clearly, our people and military contractors will rise to the occasion!</English>
		<French>C'est une déclaration de guerre! Il est évident que notre peuple et nos fournisseurs militaires sauront profiter de cette occasion!</French>
		<German>Dieser Vorfall ist ein kriegerischer Akt! Die Emp&#246;rung wird das Volk in Rage versetzen und zu H&#246;chstleistungen antreiben.</German>
		<Italian>Questo &#232; un atto di guerra! Certamente, i nostri cittadini reagiranno duramente alla notizia e i contractor militari vorranno approfittare di questa occasione!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Esto es un acto de guerra! Obviamente, nuestro pueblo y contratistas militares estaran a la altura!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT][NUM1:Tank:Tanks][COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Reçoit %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT][NUM1:Tank:Tanks][COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Ihr erhaltet %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Panzer[COLOR_REVERT]</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Ricevi %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Carri Armati[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Recibe %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Tanques[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NUCLEAR_PROTEST</Tag>
		<English>News reports indicate massive %s1_civ_adjective protests over the country's nuclear weapons stockpile.</English>
		<French>Dernière minute: manifestations %s1:4_civ_adjective contre l'arsenal nucléaire national!</French>
		<German>Es gibt Berichte &#252;ber massive %s1:3_civ_adjective B&#252;rgerproteste hinsichtlich des Atomwaffenarsenals.</German>
		<Italian>Rapporti recenti mostrano massicce proteste di cittadini %s1_civ_adjective per l'arsenale nucleare della nazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Las noticias indican protestas masivas en %s1_civ_adjective por la reserva nuclear del pais.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST</Tag>
		<English>Our people are protesting against our nuclear arsenal. They fear that we would use nukes with disastrous consequences.</English>
		<French>Nos citoyens manifestent contre notre force de frappe nucléaire. Ils craignent les conséquences dramatiques qui surviendraient si nous les utilisions.</French>
		<German>Das Volk protestiert gegen Euer Atomwaffenarsenal. Die Menschen bef&#252;rchten katastrophale Folgen durch einen Einsatz dieser Waffen.</German>
		<Italian>I nostri cittadini protestano contro il nostro arsenale nucleare. Temono che useremo le armi atomiche con conseguenze disastrose.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestro pueblo esta manifestandose contra nuestro arsenal nuclear. Temen que las usemos con consecuencias catastr&#243;ficas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_1</Tag>
		<English>The people's wishes are our top priority. We will disband our nuclear weapons.</English>
		<French>Notre priorité est de contenter nos citoyens. Nous allons désarmer notre arsenal nucléaire.</French>
		<German>Der Volkswille hat oberste Priorit&#228;t. Das Atomwaffenarsenal wird aufgel&#246;st.</German>
		<Italian>La volont&#224; del nostro popolo &#232; la nostra prima priorit&#224;. Avvia il disarmo nucleare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los deseos del pueblo son nuestra primera prioridad. Desmantelaremos nuestro arsenal nuclear.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Lose all nuclear weapons.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Perte de toutes ses armes nucléaires</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Alle Nuklearwaffen werden beseitigt</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Tutte le armi nucleari vengono smantellate.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Perder todas las armas nucleares.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_2</Tag>
		<English>What? Find those who spread such nonsense and prosecute them!</English>
		<French>De quoi? Trouvez les responsables de ces idioties et trainez-les en justice!</French>
		<German>In diesem Land entscheide ich. Lasst die Urheber der Meinungsmache strafrechtlich verfolgen!</German>
		<Italian>Cosa? Trovate chi diffonde queste sciocchezze e metteteli sotto processo!!</Italian>
		<Spanish>&#191;Qu&#233;? Encontrad a quien divulgue estas estupideces y perseguidle!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_3</Tag>
		<English>We need a positive publicity campaign for our military, right now!</English>
		<French>Il nous faut une campagne de promotion pour notre armée, tout de suite!</French>
		<German>Sorgt umgehend f&#252;r eine &#246;ffentliche Kampagne zur Unterst&#252;tzung unseres Milit&#228;rapparats!</German>
		<Italian>Le nostre forze armate hanno bisogno di una buona campagna pubblicitaria, ora!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Necesitamos una campa&#241;a de publicidad positiva para nuestro ej&#233;rcito, ahora mismo!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BETTER_COAL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective scientists have developed better ways of processing coal fuel.</English>
		<French>Les scientifiques %s1:3_civ_adjective ont développé une méthode ameliorée d'exploitation du charbon.</French>
		<German>Die %s1:2_civ_adjective Wissenschaftler entwickeln ein verbessertes Verfahren zur Energiegewinnung aus Kohle.</German>
		<Italian>Scienziati %s1_civ_adjective hanno sviluppato metodi migliori per la lavorazione del combustibile derivante dal carbone.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cient&#237;ficos %s1_civ_adjective han descubierto mejores maneras de procesar carb&#243;n.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL</Tag>
		<English>Our scientists have developed better ways of processing coal fuel. Our economy stands ready to benefit from this development.</English>
		<French>Nos scientifiques ont trouvé une meilleure facon d'exploiter le charbon. Notre économie va bénéficier énormement de cette découverte.</French>
		<German>Unsere Wissenschaftler haben ein verbessertes Verfahren zur Energiegewinnung aus Kohle entwickelt, von welchem unsere Wirtschaft profitieren k&#246;nnte.</German>
		<Italian>I nostri scienziati hanno sviluppato metodi migliori per la lavorazione del combustibile derivante dal carbone. La nostra economia &#232; pronta per beneficiare di questo sviluppo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros cient&#237;ficos han descubierto mejores maneras de procesar carb&#243;n. Nuestra economia est&#225; preparada para beneficiarse de este desarrollo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL_1</Tag>
		<English>Put it to use at our Coal-fueled power plants. Production is power!</English>
		<French>Appliquez cette avancée immediatement à nos centrales a charbon. La production, c'est le pouvoir!</French>
		<German>F&#246;rdert den Einsatz dieser Technik in unseren Kohlekraftwerken, um die st&#228;dtischen Produktionsraten zu steigern.</German>
		<Italian>Usiamolo nelle nostre centrali a carbone. La produttivit&#224; &#232; potere!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aplicadlo en nuestras plantas de carb&#243;. La producci&#243;n es poder!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL_2</Tag>
		<English>I suppose we can make our Drydocks a more healthy place to work and slightly more productive, then.</English>
		<French>J'imagine que nous pouvons faire de nos cales sèches un endroit plus sain et plus productif, alors.</French>
		<German>F&#246;rdert den Einsatz dieser Technik in unseren Trockendocks, um die dortigen Gesundheitsbedingungen und Ertr&#228;ge zu verbessern.</German>
		<Italian>Penso che i nostri cantieri navali ne gioverebbero, sarebbero luoghi pi&#249; sani per chi ci lavora e anche leggermente pi&#249; produttivi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Supongo que entonces podemos hacer de nuestros astilleros un lugar m&#225;s saludable y ligeramente m&#225;s productivo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BROKEN_DAM</Tag>
		<English>The dam in %s2_city has broken, flooding the city's suburbs and killing people.</English>
		<French>Le barrage de %s2_city a rompu, inondant les faubourgs de la ville et faisant de nombreuses victimes.</French>
		<German>Ein Bruch des Wasserschutzwalls in der Stadt %s2_city verursacht &#220;berflutungen von Stadtbezirken und fordert Todesopfer.</German>
		<Italian>La diga di %s2_city &#232; crollata. I sobborghi della citt&#224; sono stati inondati e sono state segnalate diverse persone uccise.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La presa en %s2_city ha cedido, inundando las afueras de la ciudad y matando gente.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM</Tag>
		<English>The dam in %s2_city has broken. The city's suburbs are flooded and deaths have been reported.</English>
		<French>Le barrage de %s2_city a rompu. Les banlieues de la ville sont inondées et il y a de nombreuses victimes.</French>
		<German>Ein Bruch des Wasserschutzwalls in der Stadt %s2_city verursacht &#220;berflutungen von Stadtbezirken und fordert Todesopfer.</German>
		<Italian>La diga di %s2_city &#232; crollata. I sobborghi della citt&#224; sono stati inondati e sono state segnalate diverse persone che hanno perso la vita.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La presa en %s2_city ha cedido. Las afueras de la ciudad est&#225;n inundadas y se informa de muertes.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_1</Tag>
		<English>That is very unfortunate, but we can not help. Tell the local authorities they'll have to handle the situation.</English>
		<French>C'est malheureux, mais nous ne pouvons rien y faire. Mettez les autorités locales en charge de la situation.</French>
		<German>Wir k&#246;nnen uns derzeit keine Hilfsma&#223;nahmen leisten. Die lokalen Beh&#246;rden m&#252;ssen mit dieser Situation selbst fertig werden.</German>
		<Italian>&#200; una cosa molto spiacevole, ma non possiamo fare nulla. Dici alle autorit&#224; locali che dovranno occuparsi della situazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eso es muy desafortunado, pero no podemos ayudar. Decir a las autoridades locales que tendr&#225;n que manejar la situaci&#243;n.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_2</Tag>
		<English>Repair the dam from our emergency funds.</English>
		<French>Réparez le barrage a l'aide de nos fonds d'urgence.</French>
		<German>Organisiert einen Wiederaufbau des Wasserschutzwalles.</German>
		<Italian>Ripara la diga con i nostri fondi destinati alle emergenze</Italian>
		<Spanish>Reparar la presa con nuestros fondos de emergencia.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_3</Tag>
		<English>Repair the dam and provide compensation to the affected families.</English>
		<French>Remettez le barrage en état et payez des réparations aux familles touchées par le drame.</French>
		<German>Organisiert einen Wiederaufbau des Wasserschutzwalles und Hilfsma&#223;nahmen f&#252;r die Betroffenen.</German>
		<Italian>Ripara la diga e provvedi a un risarcimento per le famiglie coinvolte dal disastro</Italian>
		<Spanish>Reparar la presa y dar compensaciones a las familias afectadas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_RABBI</Tag>
		<English>A Rabbi from %s2_city has written a valuable collection of religious works.</English>
		<French>Un rabbin de la ville de %s2_city a terminé la rédaction de son oeuvre religieuse.</French>
		<German>Ein Rabbi aus der Stadt %s2_city hat eine wertvolle Sammlung religi&#246;ser Schriften verfasst.</German>
		<Italian>Un rabbino di %s2_city ha scritto una preziosa raccolta di opere religiose</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un rabino de %s2_city ha escrito una valiosa colecci&#243;n de obras religiosas</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RABBI</Tag>
		<English>A Rabbi from %s2_city has written a collection of religious works that is of great importance to Judaism worldwide.</English>
		<French>Un rabbin de %s2_city a terminé la rédaction de son oeuvre, d'importance majeure pour le judaisme.</French>
		<German>Ein Rabbi aus der Stadt %s2_city hat eine wertvolle Sammlung religi&#246;ser Schriften verfasst, die von weltweiter Bedeutung f&#252;r das Judentum ist.</German>
		<Italian>Un rabbino di %s2_city ha scritto una preziosa raccolta di opere religiose di grande importanza per il Giudaismo nel mondo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un rabino de %s2_city ha escrito una colecci&#243;n de obras religiosas de gran valor para el judaismo mundial.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RABBI_1</Tag>
		<English>These works should be distributed to cities in our empire and abroad.</English>
		<French>Cette oeuvre doit être diffusée dans nos villes et a l'étranger!</French>
		<German>Lasst die Werke in allen St&#228;dten des Reiches und im Ausland verbreiten.</German>
		<Italian>Queste opere devono essere diffuse all'interno delle nostre citt&#224; e all'estero</Italian>
		<Spanish>Estos trabajos deben ser distribuido en las ciudades de nuestro imperio y en el extrangero</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RABBI_2</Tag>
		<English>The Rabbi certainly deserves state funding for his endeavours.</English>
		<French>Le rabbin mérite certainement une pension d'Etat pour ce qu'il a entrepris.</French>
		<German>Sorgt daf&#252;r, dass der Rabbi mit staatlicher F&#246;rderung an weiteren Werken arbeiten kann.</German>
		<Italian>Il rabbino merita sicuramente un finanziamento statale per i suoi sforzi</Italian>
		<Spanish>El rabino merece financiaci&#243;n estatal por sus esfuerzos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RABBI_3</Tag>
		<English>Works like these can easily make the local Monastery a site of interests to tourists worldwide.</English>
		<French>De tels ouvrages peuvent sûrement faire du monastère local une attraction touristique majeure!</French>
		<German>Sorgt daf&#252;r, dass das &#246;rtliche Kloster zu einem lohnenden Ziel f&#252;r Pilger und Touristen aus aller Welt wird.</German>
		<Italian>Opere come queste possono facilmente rendere il monastero locale un'attrazione turistica a livello mondiale</Italian>
		<Spanish>Trabajos como estos pueden hacer del monasterio local un lugar de interes tur&#237;stico mundial.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GOLDEN_BUDDHA</Tag>
		<English>A blacksmith from %s2_city has made a beautiful golden Buddha statue at his Forge.</English>
		<French>Un forgeron de %s2_city  a créé une superbe statue en or de Bouddha.</French>
		<German>Ein Schmied aus der Stadt %s2_city hat eine wundersch&#246;ne goldene Buddha-Statue angefertigt.</German>
		<Italian>Un fabbro di %s2_city ha creato una stupenda statua d'oro di Buddha presso la sua Fucina</Italian>
		<Spanish>La herreria de %s2_city ha realizado una hermosa estatua dorada en su forja.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA</Tag>
		<English>A blacksmith working in the Forge of %s2_city has made a beautiful golden statue of Buddha.</English>
		<French>Un forgeron travaillant dans la forge de %s2_city a créé une superbe statue en or de Bouddha.</French>
		<German>In der Schmiede der Stadt %s2_city hat der Meister eine wundersch&#246;ne goldene Buddha-Statue angefertigt.</German>
		<Italian>Un fabbro che lavora presso la fucina di %s2_city ha creato una splendida statua d'oro di Buddha</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un herrero trabajando en la forja de %s2_city ha hecho una hermosa estatua de Buda.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_1</Tag>
		<English>That's not his job. Sell the statue and remind the blacksmith what his responsibilities are.</English>
		<French>Ce n'est pas son travail. Vendez la statue et rappelez à l'ordre le forgeron.</French>
		<German>Das geh&#246;rt nicht zu seinen Aufgaben. Verkauft die Statue und erinnert den Schmied an seine Pflichten.</German>
		<Italian>Questo non &#232; il suo lavoro. Vendiamo la statua e ricorda al fabbro quali siano i suoi doveri.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ese no es su trabajo. Vende la estatua y recuerda al herrero cuales son sus responsabilidades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_2</Tag>
		<English>Impressive. This should make the Forge a cultural attraction.</English>
		<French>Impressionnant! Cette forge pourrait devenir une attraction culturelle!</French>
		<German>Beeindruckend. Die Schmiede sollte eine kulturelle Attraktion werden.</German>
		<Italian>Impressionante. Questo rendera la Fucina un'attrazione turistica.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Impresionante. Esto debe hacer de la forja una atacci&#243;n cultural.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_3</Tag>
		<English>The blacksmith is a true talent, we should encourage him to make more of these statues.</English>
		<French>Ce forgeron a un vrai talent, nous devrions l'encourager a faire plus de statues.</French>
		<German>Der Schmied ist ein Naturtalent. Ermutigt ihn zum Anfertigen weiterer Statuen.</German>
		<Italian>Questo fabbro &#232; un vero talento, incoraggiamolo a scolpire nuove statue.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El herrero es un aut&#233;ntico artista, debemos animarle a que haga m&#225;s estatuas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PREACHING_RESEARCHER</Tag>
		<English>A well-known scientist from %s2_city has become a preacher at the local Christian Monastery.</English>
		<French>Un scientifique réputé de %s2_city est rentré dans les ordres au monastère chrétien local</French>
		<German>Ein renommierter Wissenschaftler der Stadt %s2_city predigt im &#246;rtlichen Christlichen Kloster.</German>
		<Italian>Un rinomato scienziato di %s2_city &#232; diventato un predicatore presso il locale Monastero Cristiano.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un reputado cient&#237;fico de %s2_city se ha convertido en predicador en el monasterio cristiano local.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER</Tag>
		<English>A scientist from %s2_city has undergone baptism and become a preacher at the city's Christian Monastery.</English>
		<French>Un scientifique de %s2_city s'est fait baptiser et est rentré dans les ordres au monastère chrétien de la ville.</French>
		<German>Ein renommierter Wissenschaftler der Stadt %s2_city predigt nach seiner Taufe im &#246;rtlichen Christlichen Kloster.</German>
		<Italian>Uno scienziato di %s2_city si &#232; fatto battezzare ed &#232; diventato un predicatore presso il Monastero Cristiano della citt&#224;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un cient&#237;fico de %s2_city se ha bautizado y convertido en predicador en el monasterio cristiano de la ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER_1</Tag>
		<English>Send the scientist our well wishes.</English>
		<French>Envoyez au scientifique nos encouragements.</French>
		<German>&#220;bermittelt dem Wissenschaftler meine guten W&#252;nsche.</German>
		<Italian>Manda allo scienziato i nostri migliori auguri.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Envia al cient&#237;fico nuestra bendici&#243;n.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER_2</Tag>
		<English>See if the scientist would be willing to continue the scientific work at the Monastery, given some additional funding.</English>
		<French>Regardez si le scientifique serait prêt à continuer son travail au monastère s'il avait un soutien financier.</French>
		<German>Ermutigt den Wissenschaftler mit finanzieller Unterst&#252;tzung dazu, seine wissenschaftlichen Arbeiten im Kloster fortzusetzen.</German>
		<Italian>Vediamo se lo scienziato sia consenziente a continuare la propria ricerca scientifica presso il Monastero, dopo aver concesso alcuni fondi aggiuntivi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mira si el cient&#237;fico desea continuar investigando en el monasterio, d&#225;ndole alguna financiaci&#243;n adicional.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TOXCATL</Tag>
		<English>The man who is Tezcatlipoca's likeness has escaped during this year's Toxcatl feast in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<French>L'homme qui incarne Tezcatlipoca s'est échappé au cours du festival annuel de Toxcatl de l'empire %s1_civ_adjective.</French>
		<German>Im %s1:2_civ_adjective Reich gibt es einen religi&#246;sen Skandal, weil das geweihte Opfer vor der heiligen Blutzeremonie entkommen konnte.</German>
		<Italian>L'uomo che ha le sembianze di Tezcatlipoca &#232; scappato durante la celebrazione di quest'anno di Toxcatl nell'impero %s1_civ_adjective</Italian>
		<Spanish>El hombre que es el favorito de Tezcatlipoca ha huido durante el festival Toxcatl en el imperio %s1_civ_adjective.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL</Tag>
		<English>During the Toxcatl feast, the young man who is Tezcatlipoca's likeness has escaped from the teokalli in %s2_city before he could be sacrificed!</English>
		<French>Au cours du festival de Toxcatl, le jeune homme qui incarne Tezcatlipoca s'est échappé du teokalli de %s2_city avant qu'il puisse être sacrifié</French>
		<German>In der Stadt gibt %s2_city gibt es einen religi&#246;sen Skandal, weil das geweihte Opfer vor der heiligen Blutzeremonie entkommen konnte.</German>
		<Italian>Durante la celebrazione di Toxcatl un giovane uomo avente le sembianze di Tezcalipoca &#232; scappato dai teokalli nella citt&#224; di %s2_city prima che potesse essere sacrificato!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Durante el festival Toxcatl, el hombre joven favorito de Tezcatlipoca ha huido del teokalli en %s2_city antes de poder ser sacrificado!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL_1</Tag>
		<English>This is horrible news. May the heavens be merciful...</English>
		<French>Quelle horrible nouvelle. Que les cieux nous soient cléments!</French>
		<German>Schreckliche Nachricht. M&#246;gen uns die G&#246;tter gn&#228;dig sein.</German>
		<Italian>&#200; una notizia orribile! Che gli dei abbiano piet&#224;...</Italian>
		<Spanish>Terribles noticias. Que los cielos sean piadosos...</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL_2</Tag>
		<English>Make every effort to recapture him!</English>
		<French>Que tout soit fait pour le retrouver!</French>
		<German>Lasst das Opfer verfolgen und gefangen nehmen, koste es, was es wolle!</German>
		<Italian>Fate ogni sforzo per ricatturarlo!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Haz lo que sea necesario para capturarlo!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DISSIDENT_PRIEST</Tag>
		<English>A priest from %s2_city is doubting the supreme power of Amun-Re.</English>
		<French>Un prêtre de %s2_city a mis en doute le pouvoir suprême d'Amon-Re.</French>
		<German>Ein Hohepriester der Stadt %s2_city zweifelt an der Macht des Fruchtbarkeitsgottes.</German>
		<Italian>Un sacerdote di %s2_city dubita del potere supremo di Amun-Re.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un sacerdote de %s2_city duda del poder supremo de Amun-Re.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST</Tag>
		<English>A dissident priest from %s2_city is doubting the supreme power of Amun-Re in an unprecedented outbreak of heresy.</English>
		<French>Un prêtre dissident de %s2_city, a mis en doute la puissance suprême d'Amon-Re, ouvrant la voie à une nouvelle hérésie.</French>
		<German>Ein kritischer Priester der Stadt %s2_city zweifelt in beispielloser Ketzerei an der Macht des Fruchtbarkeitsgottes.</German>
		<Italian>Un sacerdote dissidente di %s2_city sta dubitando del potere supremo di Amun-Re, creando una diffusione di eresie senza precedenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>En un brote de herejia sin precedentes, un sacerdote disidente de %s2_city duda del poder supremo de Amun-Re.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_1</Tag>
		<English>That is disgusting and preposterous. The heresy must be dealt with in the name of Amun-Re, even if the locals won't support it.</English>
		<French>C'est inadmissible et dépravé. Cette hérésie doit être contrecarrée au nom d'Amon-Re, meme si les autochtones ne l'approuvent pas.</French>
		<German>Beendet im Namen des Fruchtbarkeitsgottes diese widerliche Ketzerei, notfalls mit Gewalt gegen die Bev&#246;lkerung.</German>
		<Italian>Tutto ci&#242; &#232; disgustoso e assurdo. Dovremo occuparci di questa eresia nel nome di Amun-Re, anche se non avremo l'appoggio delle popolazioni locali.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eso es lamentable y absurdo. La herejia debe ser tratada con el nombre de Amun-Re, incluso si la poblaci&#243;n local no lo apoya.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_2</Tag>
		<English>We can ignore that nutter, our people will get over it.</English>
		<French>Ignorons cet imbécile, notre peuple s'en remettra.</French>
		<German>Ignoriert den Verr&#252;ckten, das Volk wird dar&#252;ber hinweg kommen.</German>
		<Italian>Ignoriamo questo pazzo, il nostro popolo si dimenticher&#224; di tutto ci&#242; che ha detto.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Podemos ignorar esa minucia, nuestra gente se ocupara de ello.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_3</Tag>
		<English>Diversity is good. Allow these beliefs to spread and be recorded, though convincing our people that it's nothing to fear won't be easy.</English>
		<French>La diversité est positive. Laissons ces croyances se propager, meme s'il ne sera pas facile de convaincre notre peuple de leur innocuité!</French>
		<German>Der Glaube hat viele Gesichter. Zeichnet die neuen &#220;berzeugungen auf und hindert sie nicht an der Ausbreitung, aber helft den Menschen, ihren Glauben zu wahren.</German>
		<Italian>La diversit&#224; &#232; un bene.Permettiamo a questa credenza di diffondersi e di essere dichiarata ufficialmente, sebbene convincere i nostri cittadini che non c'&#232; nulla da temere sar&#224; difficile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La diversidad es buena. Permitid que esas creencias se difundad y sean preservadas, aunque convencer a nuestra gente de que no hay nada que temer no ser&#225; facil.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PASTURE_BUILT</Tag>
		<English>Industrious villagers have built a Pasture in %s1_civ_adjective lands.</English>
		<French>D'industrieux villageois ont construit une pâture dans les terres %s1:4_civ_adjective</French>
		<German>Flei&#223;ige Dorfbewohner errichten auf %s1:3_civ_adjectivem Boden selbst&#228;ndig eine Weide.</German>
		<Italian>Abitanti industriosi di un villaggio hanno costruito un Pascolo nelle terre %s1_civ_adjective</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aldeanos laboriosos han hecho un pastizal en tierras de %s1_civ_adjective.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PASTURE_BUILT</Tag>
		<English>Industrious villagers near our city of %s2_city have built a Pasture.</English>
		<French>D'industrieux villageois ont construit une pâture près de la ville de %s2_city.</French>
		<German>Flei&#223;ige Dorfbewohner errichten nahe der Stadt %s2_city selbst&#228;ndig eine Weide.</German>
		<Italian>Abitanti industriosi di un villaggio vicino alla nostra citt&#224; di %s2_city hanno costruito un Pascolo</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aldeanos laboriosos cerca de la ciudad de %s2_city han hecho un pastizal.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PASTURE_BUILT_1</Tag>
		<English>Send them our thanks.</English>
		<French>Envoyez-leur nos remerciements!</French>
		<German>&#220;bermittelt meinen Dank.</German>
		<Italian>Manda i nostri ringraziamenti</Italian>
		<Spanish>Darles las gracias.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ROGUE_STATION</Tag>
		<English>A rogue radio station in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city is broadcasting propaganda against the ruling party.</English>
		<French>Une radio pirate dans la ville %s1:2_civ_adjective de %s2_city diffuse de la propagande anti-gouvernementale.</French>
		<German>Im %s1:2_civ_adjective Reich verbreitet ein Piratensender ausgehend von der Stadt %s2_city Propaganda gegen die Regierung.</German>
		<Italian>Una stazione radio dissidente nella citt&#224; %s1_civ_adjective di %s2_city sta diffondendo propaganda contro il partito al potere</Italian>
		<Spanish>Una emisora pirata en la ciudad %s1_civ_adjective de %s2_city est&#225; emitiendo propaganda contra el partido gobernante.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION</Tag>
		<English>A rogue radio station in %s2_city is broadcasting propaganda against our ruling party in an amazing display of impudence.</English>
		<French>Une radio pirate de %s2_city diffuse de façon ouverte et insolente de la propagande anti-gouvernementale.</French>
		<German>Ein Piratensender verbreitet ausgehend von der Stadt %s2_city dreiste Propaganda gegen Eure Regierung.</German>
		<Italian>Una stazione radio dissidente nella citt&#224; di %s2_city sta diffondendo propaganda contro il nostro partito al potere, mostrando una sorprendente impudenza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Una emisora pirata en %s2_city est&#225; emitiendo propaganda contra nuestro partido gobernante en una sorprendente muestra de imprudencia.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_1</Tag>
		<English>Send a blackops group to destroy the radio tower, we can blame it on an industrial accident.</English>
		<French>Envoyez le GIGN détruire la station émettrice, nous prétendrons que c'est un accident industriel.</French>
		<German>Ein verdecktes Einsatzkommando soll den Sender zerst&#246;ren, aber lasst es wie einen Unfall aussehen.</German>
		<Italian>Manda una squadra speciale a distruggere la stazione radio, possiamo addossare le cause ad un incidente industriale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Envia un grupo encubierto a destruir la torre de radio, podemos disfrazarlo de accidente industrial.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_2</Tag>
		<English>Round up the broadcasters, that should send a message.</English>
		<French>Envoyez les animateurs au trou, ca devrait faire passer le message.</French>
		<German>Lasst die Betreiber verhaften, das sollte als Warnung gen&#252;gen.</German>
		<Italian>Catturate gli annunciatori, capiranno il messaggio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Apresa a los locutores, eso enviar&#225; un mensaje.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_3</Tag>
		<English>Wait for the station to get more listeners, then round them up along with the broadcasters and send them all to do labour at our factories.</English>
		<French>Attendez que la station gagne des auditeurs, puis arrêtez-le ainsi que les animateurs et envoyez tout le monde travailler dans nos usines.</French>
		<German>Stellt fest, wer mit dem Piratensender sympathisiert, dann verhaftet die Staatsfeinde und verurteilt sie zur Zwangsarbeit in den Fabriken.</German>
		<Italian>Attendete che alla stazione radio si radunino vari ascoltatori, poi catturate gli annunciatori e tutti gli ascoltatori che si erano radunati e mandateli ai lavori forzati nelle nostre fabbriche.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Espera a que la emisora tenga m&#225;s oyentes, entonces apr&#233;salos junto a los locutores y envialos a trabajar a nuestras f&#225;bricas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANTIMONARCHISTS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective antimonarchists are protesting, saying that the religious institutions don't have enough power compared to the King.</English>
		<French>Des anti-monarchistes %s1:3_civ_adjective manifestent car ils trouvent que les institutions religieuses ne sont pas assez puissantes comparées au roi.</French>
		<German>Im %s1:2_civ_adjective Reich protestieren gl&#228;ubige Menschen gegen die Ohnmacht religi&#246;ser Institutionen im Vergleich zur Allmacht des K&#246;nigshauses.</German>
		<Italian>Gli antimonarchici %s1_civ_adjective stanno protestando, dicono che le istituzioni religiose non hanno abbastanza poteri rispetto al re.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antimon&#225;rquicos %s1_civ_adjective estan protestando, diciendo que las instituciones religiosas apenas tiene poder frente al Rey.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS</Tag>
		<English>Anti-monarchists are claiming that the King has too much power and that religious leaders need to have some, too.</English>
		<French>Des anti-monarchistes prétendent que le roi a trop de pouvoir, et que les autorités religieuses devraient en avoir plus.</French>
		<German>Gl&#228;ubige Menschen protestieren gegen die Ohnmacht religi&#246;ser Institutionen im Vergleich zur Allmacht Eures K&#246;nigshauses.</German>
		<Italian>Gli antimonarchici rivendicano che il Re ha troppi poteri, e che i leader religiosi debbano avere i propri poteri rafforzati.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Antimon&#225;rquicos reclaman qu&#233; el rey tiene demasiado poder y qu&#233; los lideres religiosos deberian tener algo tambien.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our King is the State!</English>
		<French>L'Etat, c'est moi!</French>
		<German>Der Staat bin ich!</German>
		<Italian>Il Re &#232; lo Stato!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestro rey es el estado!</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS_2</Tag>
		<English>It's a valid point, our clerics need more influence.</English>
		<French>Ce sont de justes revendications, notre clergé a besoin d'être plus influent.</French>
		<German>Nun gut, ich gew&#228;hre den Geistlichen mehr Einfluss.</German>
		<Italian>Hanno ragione, le organizzazioni ecclesiastiche devono avere pi&#249; influenza.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Es un argumento v&#225;lido, nuestro clerigos necesitan m&#225;s influencia.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_IMPEACHMENT</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective President is facing impeachment.</English>
		<French>Le président %s1_civ_adjective fait face à une motion de censure.</French>
		<German>Im %s1:2_civ_adjective Reich droht der Regierungsf&#252;hrung ein Amtsenthebungsverfahren.</German>
		<Italian>Il Presidente %s1_civ_adjective &#232; stato messo sotto impeachment</Italian>
		<Spanish>El presidente %s1_civ_adjective se enfrente a una moci&#243;n de censura.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT</Tag>
		<English>The Congress wants to impeach the President. The population supports this motion.</English>
		<French>Les députés, soutenus par la population, souhaitent passer une motion de censure à l'égard du président.</French>
		<German>Der Kongress verlangt ein Amtsenthebungsverfahren gegen die Regierungsf&#252;hrung, unterst&#252;tzt von gro&#223;en Teilen der Bev&#246;lkerung.</German>
		<Italian>Il Congresso vuole mettere sotto impeachment il Presidente. La popolazione supporta la mozione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El congreso ha presentado una moci&#243;n de censura contra el presidente. La poblaci&#243;n apoya esta iniciativa.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT_1</Tag>
		<English>Then the impeachment should proceed, if that's the people's will.</English>
		<French>Que la motion passe, si c'est le souhait du peuple.</French>
		<German>Ist es der Wille des Volkes, so m&#246;ge das Amtsenthebungsverfahren beginnen.</German>
		<Italian>Se &#232; la volont&#224; del popolo, l'impeachment deve andare avanti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Entonces la moci&#243;n debe proceder, si es el deseo del pueblo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT_2</Tag>
		<English>That's an overreaction. The President has gotten the message that his administration needs to improve.</English>
		<French>Ils en font trop. Le président devrait comprendre le message et rénover son administration.</French>
		<German>Ein Amtsenthebungsverfahren w&#228;re &#252;bertrieben. Aber die Regierungsf&#252;hrung soll die Sorgen der Menschen ernster nehmen.</German>
		<Italian>&#200; una reazione eccessiva. Il Presidente avr&#224; inteso il messaggio che la sua amministrazione deve migliorare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Eso es una exageraci&#243;n. El presidente debe captar el mensaje de que su administraci&#243;n debe mejorar.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EARTHDAY_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Persuade other nations to convert to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Environmentalism[COLOR_REVERT] (at least one civilization must have the ability to do so).</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Persuader d'autres nations de se convertir à l'[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]écologie[COLOR_REVERT] (au moins une civilisation doit posséder cette capacité).</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]&#220;berzeugt andere Nationen, zum [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Umweltschutz[COLOR_REVERT] zu wechseln (mindestens eine Zivilisation muss dazu f&#228;hig sein).</German>
		<Italian>[ICON_BULLET]Persuadi altre nazioni a convertirsi all'[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ambientalismo[COLOR_REVERT] (almeno una delle altre civilt&#224; deve essere in grado di farlo).</Italian>
		<Spanish>[ICON_BULLET]Convence a otras naciones de que se conviertan al [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ecologismo[COLOR_REVERT] (al menos una civilizaci&#243;n debe poseer la capacidad de hacerlo).</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SALTPETER_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>Saltpeter Discovered.</English>
		<French>Salpêtre découvert.</French>
		<German>Salpeter entdeckt.</German>
		<Italian>Scoperto il salnitro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Has descubierto el salitre.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_OLYMPICS</Tag>
   		<English>All records of ancient games have been forever lost.</English>
   		<French>Toutes les informations sur les jeux antiques ont &#233;t&#233; perdues pour toujours.</French>
   		<German>Alle Informationen &#252;ber die alte Spiele sind f&#252;r immer verloren worden.</German>
   		<Italian>Tutte le informazioni sui giochi antichi sono state perse per sempre.</Italian>
   		<Spanish>Toda la informaci&#243;n sobre los juegos antiguos se ha perdido por siempre.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORSE_WHISPERING</Tag>
		<English>Our horse trainers believe that it would be possible to gain a much deeper bond with and understanding of our riding animals.[PARAGRAPH:1]They require a larger and more coordinated network of [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stables[COLOR_REVERT] to pursue this goal.</English>
		<French>Nos entra&#238;neurs de chevaux pensent qu'on peut cr&#233;er un lien plus profond avec nos montures et les comprendre davantage.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ils ont besoin d'un r&#233;seau d'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Ecuries[COLOR_REVERT] plus grand et mieux coordonn&#233; pour y parvenir.</French>
		<German>Unsere Pferdetrainer glauben, dass ein viel innigeres Band und ein tieferes Verst&#228;ndnis im Umgang mit unseren Reittieren m&#246;glich w&#228;re.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sie verlangen ein gr&#246;&#223;eres und koordinierteres Netz von [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]St&#228;llen[COLOR_REVERT], um dieses Ziel zu erreichen.</German>
		<Italian>I nostri allevatori di cavalli credono che sia possibile ottenere un maggiore legame e una pi&#249; profonda comprensione dei nostri animali.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hanno bisogno di una rete pi&#249; coordinata di [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stalle[COLOR_REVERT] per raggiungere questo obiettivo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Nuestros adiestradores de caballos creen que ser&#237;a posible establecer un v&#237;nculo m&#225;s profundo con nuestros animales de montura.[PARAGRAPH:1]Necesitan una red de [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Establos[COLOR_REVERT] para tratar de alcanzar este objetivo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MIRACLE</Tag>
		<English>A miracle performed at the city wall in %s2_city is attracting %s3_religion_adjective pilgrims from far and wide.</English>
		<French>Un miracle accompli au pied des murs de la ville de %s2_city attire des p&#232;lerins %s3:3_religion_adjective de loin.</French>
		<German>Ein Wunder, das an der Stadtmauer von %s2_city geschehen ist, lockt %s3:3_religion_adjective Pilger aus nah und fern an.</German>
		<Italian>Un miracolo accaduto al muro della citt&#224; di %s2_city sta attirando pellegrini %s3_religion_adjective da ogni dove.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Un milagro realizado en la muralla de %s2_city est&#225; atrayendo a peregrinos %s3:3_religion_adjective de distintos y lejanos lugares.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HAPPY_HUNTING</Tag>
		<English>Surplus game harvested by hunters near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city has fueled a minor population boom.</English>
		<French>Un surplus de gibier d&#233;busqu&#233; par des chasseurs %s1:3_civ_adjective pr&#232;s de la ville de %s2_city a donn&#233; lieu &#224; une brusque hausse de la population.</French>
		<German>Das von J&#228;gern in der N&#228;he der %s1:2_civ_adjective Stadt %s2_city erbeutete zus&#228;tzliche Wild hat einen geringen Bev&#246;lkerungszuwachs bewirkt.</German>
		<Italian>L'abbondante selvaggina procurata dai cacciatori vicino alla citt&#224; %s1_civ_adjective di %s2_city ha causato un piccolo boom demografico.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El excedente logrado por los cazadores cerca de la ciudad %s1:2_civ_adjective de %s2_city ha impulsado un peque&#241;o crecimiento de la poblaci&#243;n.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CITY_RUINS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective explorers have discovered valuable information buried in ruins near %s2_city.</English>
		<French>Des explorateurs %s1:3_civ_adjective ont d&#233;couvert des informations cruciales en fouillant les ruines pr&#232;s de %s2_city.</French>
		<German>%s1:3_civ_adjective Kundschafter haben in den Ruinen nahe %s2_city wertvolle Informationen entdeckt.</German>
		<Italian>Esploratori %s1_civ_adjective hanno scoperto preziose informazioni nascoste nelle rovine vicine a %s2_city.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Exploradores %s1:3_civ_adjective han descubierto una valiosa informaci&#243;n enterrada en las ruinas cercanas a %s2_city.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GREAT_BEAST</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective hunters have discovered a great beast lurking near one of their camps.</English>
		<French>Les chasseurs %s1:3_civ_adjective ont découvert une énorme bête rodant près d'un de leurs camps.</French>
		<German>Von %s1:2_civ_adjective J&#228;gern gibt es Berichte &#252;ber ein riesiges Tier, das sich in der N&#228;he eines Lagers gezeigt haben soll.</German>
		<Italian>Cacciatori %s1_civ_adjective hanno avvistato un grande animale appostato nei dintorni di un loro accampamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cazadores %s1_civ_adjective han descubierto una gran bestia acechando uno de sus campamentos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SECURITY_TAX</Tag>
		<English>The well-protected %s1_civ_adjective citizens endure paying a Security Tax to help maintain their city walls and guards.</English>
		<French>En &#233;change d'une bonne protection, les citoyens %s1:3_civ_adjective doivent subir un Imp&#244;t S&#233;curitaire pour aider au maintien des murs et des gardes de leur ville.</French>
		<German>Die gut gesch&#252;tzten %s1:2_civ_adjective B&#252;rger zahlen eine Sicherheitssteuer, um die Stadtmauern und die Wachen zu finanzieren.</German>
		<Italian>I cittadini %s1_civ_adjective, che sono ben protetti, accettano di pagare una tassa di sicurezza per mantenere mura e guardie della citt&#224;.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los ciudadanos %s1:3_civ_adjective est&#225;n bien protegidos. Soportan el pago de un impuesto de seguridad para contribuir al mantenimiento de las murallas y guardias de su ciudad.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>

</Civ4GameText>
