<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- ###################################################################################### -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TERRACOTTA</Tag>
		<English>Terracotta Army</English>
		<French>Armée en Terre-Cuite</French>
		<German>Terrakotta-Armee</German>
		<Italian>Terracotta Army</Italian>
		<Spanish>Terracotta Army</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TERRACOTTA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Terracotta Army are the Terra Cotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang the First Emperor of China. The terracotta figures, dating from 210 BCE, were discovered in 1974 by some local farmers near Xi'an, Shaanxi province, China near the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor.  The figures vary in height (183–195 cm - 6ft–6ft 5in), according to their role, the tallest being the generals. The figures include strong warriors, chariots, horses, officials, acrobats, strongmen, and musicians. Current estimates are that in the three pits containing the Terracotta Army there were over 8,000 soldiers, 130 chariots with 520 horses and 150 cavalry horses, the majority of which are still buried in the pits.</English>
		<French>Le mausolée de Xi'an (bingma yong en pinyin) qui s'étend sur environ 56 km², est un mausolée dédié à l'empereur Qin Shi Huangdi (IIIe siècle av. J.-C.). L'ensemble archéologique, qui se trouve à proximité de la ville de Xi'an, comprend d'une part le tombeau proprement dit, et d'autre part les fosses où l'on a trouvé, à partir de 1974, l'armée enterrée formée par des milliers de soldats de terre cuite. Cette dernière est parfois appelée armée de terre cuite (en anglais terracotta army) ou armée d'argile. Les premiers guerriers ont été découverts par des cultivateurs qui creusaient un puits dans un village voisin. Rapidement, les fouilles ont commencé, et de larges bâtiments ont été édifiés pour les protéger. Le premier a été terminé en 1979. On trouve beaucoup de fantassins, mais aussi des archers, des chars, des cavaliers, des généraux, etc. Détail des chevauxLes personnages mesurent près de 1,80 m à 2 m, et ont tous un visage différent grâce à un jeu d'assemblage des différents éléments composants le visage. Ils portent tous une arme (épée, arc, arbalète) en bronze recouverte d'une fine couche de chrome (raison pour laquelle certaines de ces armes sont toujours affûtées) ; certaines d'entre elles auraient été pillées ou en partie retirées par des archéologues pour les analyser ou les exposer dans un musée, mais on peut encore distinguer leur trace dans la forme des mains.</French>
		<German>The Terracotta Army are the Terra Cotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang the First Emperor of China. The terracotta figures, dating from 210 BCE, were discovered in 1974 by some local farmers near Xi'an, Shaanxi province, China near the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor.  The figures vary in height (183–195 cm - 6ft–6ft 5in), according to their role, the tallest being the generals. The figures include strong warriors, chariots, horses, officials, acrobats, strongmen, and musicians. Current estimates are that in the three pits containing the Terracotta Army there were over 8,000 soldiers, 130 chariots with 520 horses and 150 cavalry horses, the majority of which are still buried in the pits.</German>
		<Italian>The Terracotta Army are the Terra Cotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang the First Emperor of China. The terracotta figures, dating from 210 BCE, were discovered in 1974 by some local farmers near Xi'an, Shaanxi province, China near the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor.  The figures vary in height (183–195 cm - 6ft–6ft 5in), according to their role, the tallest being the generals. The figures include strong warriors, chariots, horses, officials, acrobats, strongmen, and musicians. Current estimates are that in the three pits containing the Terracotta Army there were over 8,000 soldiers, 130 chariots with 520 horses and 150 cavalry horses, the majority of which are still buried in the pits.</Italian>
		<Spanish>The Terracotta Army are the Terra Cotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang the First Emperor of China. The terracotta figures, dating from 210 BCE, were discovered in 1974 by some local farmers near Xi'an, Shaanxi province, China near the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor.  The figures vary in height (183–195 cm - 6ft–6ft 5in), according to their role, the tallest being the generals. The figures include strong warriors, chariots, horses, officials, acrobats, strongmen, and musicians. Current estimates are that in the three pits containing the Terracotta Army there were over 8,000 soldiers, 130 chariots with 520 horses and 150 cavalry horses, the majority of which are still buried in the pits.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TERRACOTTA_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Terracotta Army[COLOR_REVERT] Increases enemy's War Weariness and your Great General rate; also adds one Population to all your cities.</English>
		<French>L'[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Armée en Terre Cuite[COLOR_REVERT] augmente le mécontentement lié à la Guerre de vos ennemis, et facilite l'apparition d'un Général Illustre. Ajoute également 1 de population dans toutes vos Villes.</French>
		<German>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Terrakotta-Armee[COLOR_REVERT] Erh&#246;ht die Kriegsm&#252;digkeit der Feinde und beschleunigt die Bildung von Gro&#223;en Gener&#228;len. Erh&#246;ht zudem die Bev&#246;lkerung von allen St&#228;dten um 1.</German>
		<Italian>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Terracotta Army[COLOR_REVERT] Increases enemy's War Weariness and your Great General rate; also adds one Population to all your cities.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Terracotta Army[COLOR_REVERT] Increases enemy's War Weariness and your Great General rate; also adds one Population to all your cities.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>